Ishwarya Saran

Apt 3, 46A Barrack Street, Cork City, Co. Cork, T12 VY81

Tel: +353 89 9843336, E-mail: ishwaryasaran96@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ishwaryasaran/

A recent graduate of design and development from University College Cork, who is driven by new technologies. 3+ years experience in a multinational information technology services and consulting company. I am looking to utilize my current technical and analytical skills to help me further develop these skills in a practical and fast-paced environment.

SKILLS AND CERTIFICATION

- IT Skills Java, HTML and CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Jira Tool, Github, Microsoft Office, Unified Functional Testing (UFT), Adobe Creative Suite.
- Knowledge in Design principles, such as color theory and typography, Agile methodology, Troubleshooting and testing skills, UX and UI design, Web frameworks, API design.
- Completed Figma UI/UX Design Essential Training from Udemy
- Completed Web Development Bootcamp from Udemy

EDUCATION

2021 – 2022, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland. (Partial Scholarship)

M.Sc. Design and Development of Digital Business(DDDB).

Key Modules: Programming for Web Application and Services, Object-Oriented Programming using Java, Database Analysis, Mobile Application Development, Business Models and Interaction Design.

Overall Grade: 2.1 honours (GPA)

Project work:

- E Commerce Website for the local businesses using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap.

2014 - 2017, Lady Doak College, Tamil Nadu, India.

Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Travglen T/A McDonald's Crew Trainer Cork, Ireland September 2021 - Present

- Providing training to new employees.
- Trained in all areas of customer service and kitchen operations.
- evaluating the performance of new employees and providing feedback and coaching as needed.
- Assisting with employee development identifying learning opportunities and providing ongoing coaching and support.
- Maintaining compliance with company procedures and policies.

Cognizant Technology Solutions Programmer Analyst Chennai, India June 2018 - August 2021

- Experience in web testing created and issued policies in applications.
- Validated the EPW copies for all the transactions and forms.
- Consolidated the defects and observations of the team daily basis and shared the same with the development team for fix and tracked it till closure.
- Involved in Test plan, Test case preparation, Task allocation, daily and weekly status report and Iteration summary report.
- Performed Functional testing, Regression testing, Retesting and UAT.
- Experience in testing Quick pdf (on demand request) for the transactions.
- Involved in sharing the forms with business for UAT review and sign off. Executed the scripts for Policy issuance and analyzed the reports.
- Reviewing Peer's deliverables.
- Mentoring new associates on Application, Test Conditions, Test Cases and QC Process.

Edyoo Technologies

Graphic Design Intern Bangalore, India

May 2018 - June 2018

- Participated in design team meetings, helped with design projects and social media, conduct client research, and collaborated with experienced designers for the projects.
- Design and develop graphic design projects for print, digital or other media.
- Develop a portfolio of work that will be used to support the company's strategy.
- Work with clients on creative ideas in order to create compelling visual content using Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop/Premiere Pro/After Effects/InDesign/Illustrator).
- Create layouts from scratch as needed, using Photoshop or Illustrator.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

UCC LGBTO Society

Social Media Officer

October 2021 - July 2022

- Monitoring social media channels to respond appropriately to posts / comments, and identifying issues that require escalation.
- Promoting the events and activities organized by the society in the social media.

CoVID19India Org

Design and Social Media

April 2020 - April 2021

- Design and develop graphic design projects for digital or other media.
- Creating the layout for the website using Adobe Photoshop.